new-list.com 2002-12-09

# New-List.com, Privacy Statement

**Privacy Statement for New-List.com**  
  
**Subscription Forms**  
  
New-List.com uses subscription forms for individuals to request information by subscribing to Email Newsletters based on their categories of interest. We collect visitor's contact information (like your email address) to provide you with the information that you request. We will periodically send you email referring to news and updates to List-Universe.com.  
  
**Choice / Opt-In**  
  
We provide opt-in opportunities for all email lists that you choose to receive. We use your email addresses to confirm your subscription and validity of the provided email address. Your reply to this email is necessary for completing your subscription to any email list.  
  
**IP Address**  
  
We use your IP address, browser type, domain names, and access times, operating system, country of origin, page views, and users sessions to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer our Web site. Your IP, etc. address is used to gather broad demographic information. Your IP address is used to gather broad demographic information.  
  
**Cookies**  
  
A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user's computer. We use a third party advertisement server to serve ads on our site. Our site only uses session ID cookies for this third party advertisement server to deliver proper ad rotation sequences. For example, if three banners are in rotation, the individual gets the proper rotation without duplicates. Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to personally identifiable information while on our site. Further, once a user closes their browser the cookie simply terminates.  
  
**Links**  
  
This site contains links to other sites. New-List.com is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites. New-List.com recommends you refer to each Network Member's Privacy Statements.

New-List.com uses subscription forms for individuals to request information by subscribing to Email Newsletters based on their categories of interest. We collect visitor's contact information (like your email address) to provide you with the information that you request. We will periodically send you email referring to news and updates to New-List.com.  
  
**Sharing Information**  
  
New-List.com does not share, sell or rent your email addresses to outside third parties. See our Third Party Information/List Referral Section below. Personally identifiable information will only be disclosed due to law or court demands (see our legal disclaimer below for more information).  
  
**Submission Form**  
  
All information collected via the Submission Form is used by New-List.com solely for the purpose of compiling the weekly email newsletter and site additions.   
  
**Supplementation of Information**  
  
We do not supplement your personally identifiable information with any outside third parties information.  
  
**Security**  
  
The New-List.com web site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. Sensitive data, such as credit card information, collected through New-List.com's website is transferred via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) server only. New-List.com employees are made aware of all security policies and are maintaining and protecting your personally identifiable information.   
  
**Third-party Advertising**  
  
New-List.com uses third-party advertising software. This software tracks banner click-throughs, via IP address. The anonymity of the user is preserved because no personally identifiable information is tied to the click-through data.   
  
**Correct / Update**  
  
Change the email address that you have subscribed with by first unsubscribing with your current email address. Then, resubscribe with your new email address. All email list welcome messages contain the information necessary for subscription and removal from their appropriate list.  
  
**Third Party Information/List Referrals**  
  
If you opt-in to receive the topics displayed on the "thank you" page, your name, email address, zipcode and any other identifying information that you give us will not be revealed to any of the direct marketers who rent our lists. When you sign up for the PostMasterDirect.com mailing lists, you will receive commercial email messages only about those topical categories that you have selected. Before any mailing goes out, their staff personally screens each marketer's message to make sure that it's relevant to the list's topic. Every PostMasterDirect.com message sent out is coded with a special header and footer that allows you to remove your name from all lists automatically by forwarding the message to [deleteall@postmasterdirect.com](mailto:deleteall@postmasterdirect.com).   
  
**Notification of Changes**  
  
New-List.com will occasionally update our privacy policy based on our employees' and users' feedback. If there are any material changes to how we use your personal information, we will notify via email and provide you the opportunity to opt-out prior to any substantial change that has been taken. However, if you have opted out of all communication from List-Universer.com you will not be contacted, nor will your personal information be used in this new manner. List-Universe.com encourages you to periodically review our privacy policy to be informed of how we are committed to protecting your privacy.   
  
**Unsubscribe**  
  
We provide unsubscribe / opt-out opportunities for all email lists that you choose to receive. All email list welcome messages contain the information necessary for removal from the list. Removal from all lists is instant and automated by our servers.  
  
**Legal Disclaimer**  
  
Though we make every effort to preserve your privacy, we may need to disclose personal information when required by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary in order to conform to the edicts of the law or comply with a legal process served on our Web site.  
  
**Contacting the Web Site**  
  
If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, you can contact: 

Christopher M. Knight  
New-List.com  
1592 Union Street, Suite 185  
San Francisco, CA 94123
